Neng Wang

wangneng100@gmail.com 🥒 8326709815

1 PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Architect with 10+ years experience on Enterprise Products, About 6 years iPaaS Cloud experiences. Working on the world's most powerful integration platform TIBCO Cloud Integration(iPaaS) as Architect, In-depth knowledge of Data Refining and Integration products. Good experience with Amazon Web Services(Amazon S3, EC2, RDS, EFS, Route53, EKS, Elasticsearch etc.)

Responsible for product and software architecture, design and lead the implementation, Delivered many integration products and currently work on TIBCO Clarity and TIBCO AuditSafe for more than 5 years.

Specialties.

- · System Architect, Design and Development.
- Data Refining, Elasticsearch, Integration Cloud, CICD
- Microservices, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Fluentbit, AKS, EKS
- Java, Python, REST API's, OAuth2

EXPERIENCE

• Architect | TIBCO Software Inc. | Stafford, TX

May 2019 - Present

- Analysis Elasticsearch performance issue, redesign the indices schema and refactory the backend code. Improve the response speed for more than 30%.
- Provide technical expertise and leadership in the design, development, and delivery of TIBCO AuditSafe Enterprise Edition using Spring Boot, Docker, and Kubernetes technologies.
- Design the CI/CD system of TIBCO Business Connector and TIBCO AuditSafe Enterprise Edition with TeamCity.
- Design and implement TIBCO Flogo Connector and BusinessWorks Plugin for TIBCO AuditSafe and TIBCO Clarity.
- Lead developer team to design and develop TIBCO Clarity Cloud and integrate with TIBCO Spotfire and TIBCO EBX.
- Collaborate across teams in brainstorming; review and research top technologies to recommend tools, frameworks, and best practices to improve the stability, performance, and quality of our products.

• Senior Software Engineer | Pactera NA Inc. | Stafford, TX

Dec 2015 – May 2019

- Design and implement TIBCO AuditSafe Cloud.
- Implement the build and deploy system for TIBCO AuditSafe Cloud. Using Gradle, Docker and AWS technologies.
- Designing, Programming for TIBCO Clarity on Cloud. Integration Clairty to TIBCO Cloud and Implement new feature for the product.
- Senior Software Engineer | Pactera Technology Limited | Beijing, China May 2011-- Dec 2015
 - Programming, Testing for TCT (Tibco Configuration Tool) with OSGI framework.

- Programming, Testing for Clarity. Main modules are: Activespaces, MDM, Vaule, Spotfire connector and Cloud Storage. Cloud Storage includes Google Drive, Dropbox, and Box.
- Demand analysis, Programming, Testing and Files management for Business Event Channels.
- Software Engineer | Taiji Computer Corporation Limited | Beijing, China Jul 2009 -- April 2011
 - Demand analysis, Programming, Testing and Files management for Public Health Emergency Commanding and Decision-Making System of Yunnan Province.
 - Took part in 2010 Health Information Technology Conference in Xiamen and made on-site demonstration.

Education

M.Eng. in Software Engineering,
M.Eng. in Telecommunications Engineering
B.Sc. in Software Engineering,
Wuhan University
Dublin City University
Wuhan University
09/2007 – 09/2008
Wuhan University
09/2002 – 07/2006

Aword

- 2015.2 Model Trainee of Pactera PMA program
- 2013.1 Best Development Group of TIBCO CDC
- 2012.1 Excellent staff of TIBCO CDC
- 2011.1 Excellent staff of Taiji
- 2010.1 Best Development Award Individual Winner